hertz.co.uk 2014-04-28

# 

 **  Privacy Policy**

 **YOUR PRIVACY:**  We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting the personal data we hold about you. This policy explains what data we collect about you, how we collect it, the measures we take to keep your data secure and the uses we make of it. We also explain the options you have regarding your personal data. When you request services from us, access our websites, utilize our mobile “apps” or otherwise interact with us, for example, but without limitation, through our kiosks, our in-vehicle or in-equipment technology, our official corporate pages on third party social networks (such as Facebook) or the “apps” on those pages, you consent to our collection, retention and use of your personal data in the manner described in this policy and accept the risks outlined in the Security section. You can quickly review the key topics by reading the following overview or you may continue to scroll down to read more about an issue or to read the full policy.

 **Scope **

 **Who we are:**  We are The Hertz Corporation and its subsidiaries. This policy does not cover our licensees or affiliates. This policy does not cover our Dollar Rent A Car, our Thrifty Rent A Car or our Firefly Rent A Car businesses, or our Donlen Corporation subsidiary.

 **Legal Issues:**  We aim to comply with the privacy laws applicable to the personal data we collect and use.

 **Changes:**  We may change this policy from time to time. The policy was **_last updated_** on **1  April 2013**.

| 

 **Collection **

 **What we collect:**  We collect the personal data we need to provide the services you request from us, for our operational uses (see below) or for such other purposes as you authorize.

 **Sources:**  We mostly collect your data directly from you and companies involved in our provision of services to you, including our licensees.

 **Websites:**  Certain technologies are used on our websites, our apps and other ecommerce media including cookies and Pixel Tags, to collect data about your visit to our site and sites upon which we advertise. You may choose to restrict the use of cookies as suggested in this policy.  
  
---|---  
  
 **Retention **

 **Storage:**  We generally retain personal data about our customers for as long as we believe appropriate for the purposes for which it was collected.

 **Security:**  We aim to maintain appropriate physical, procedural and electronic safeguards to protect your personal data.

 **Access:**  You may access and review the personal data we retain about you and correct any factual errors.

| 

 **Use **

 **Operational Uses:**  By providing your personal data to us, you consent to our use and disclosure of your data for the operational purposes listed in this policy.

 **Marketing Uses:**  We would like to use your personal data for our marketing purposes. We may also want to share your data with our business partners for their marketing purposes. You can choose to restrict these uses by following the instructions in this policy.  
  
 **CONTACT US:**  We hope this policy answers your questions about our collection and use of your personal data. If it does not, or if you have any questions, please contact us by following the instructions in the Contact Us section below.

 **Privacy Policy**

 **YOUR PRIVACY**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting the personal data we hold about you. This policy explains what data we collect about you, how we collect it, the measures we take to keep your data secure and the uses we make of it. We also explain the options you have in relation to your personal data.

When you request services from us, operate a vehicle or equipment with in-vehicle or in-equipment technology, access our websites, utilize our mobile “apps” or otherwise interact with us, for example, but without limitation, through our kiosks, our official corporate pages on third party social networks (such as Facebook) or the “apps” on those pages, you consent to our collection, retention and use of your personal data in the manner described in this policy and accept the risks outlined in the Security section.

 **SCOPE** This policy covers the personal data we collect about you in connection with our vehicle and equipment rental business which identifies you as an individual. It does not address data that does not personally identify you as an individual, for example, but without limitation, aggregated anonymous data, IP addresses, computer operating systems, personal preferences, vehicle identification numbers, etc. We are free to use data that does not identify you as an individual as we wish. This policy does not apply to data collected by third party social networks (such as Facebook), mobile device manufacturers, third party “mobile apps”, wireless service providers, internet service providers or the operators of any networks through which you may interact with us and we expressly disclaim any responsibility for the data collection, privacy or data security practices of those entities. With regard to pages on third party social networks, this policy only applies to personal data we collect through our pages (those with a direct link to this policy) and does not apply to any “unofficial” pages or pages of our affiliates or licensees. Our websites are not directed to individuals under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly obtain personal data from such individuals.

 **Who we are    
**\--------------------------------------------------------

We are The Hertz Corporation, a U.S. company based in New Jersey, which, together with our subsidiary companies, provides and supports vehicle and equipment rental services worldwide. All references in this policy to “we”, “us” and “our” are to us and our subsidiaries. Our businesses generally operate under a “Hertz” mark, including Hertz Rent A Car, Hertz Local Edition, Hertz on Demand 24/7 (formerly known as Connect by Hertz), Hertz Claims Management, and Hertz Equipment Rental Corporation. In addition, our subsidiary Navigation Solutions, LLC, which provides the Hertz NeverLost service, is also covered by this policy. However, neither our Dollar Rent A Car or Thrifty Rent A Car businesses operated by Dollar Thrifty Automotive Group, Inc., a Hertz subsidiary, our Firefly Rent A Car business, nor our Donlen Corporation subsidiary are covered by this policy because each of those entities/operations has its own privacy policy. We also operate equipment rental businesses and, to a lesser extent, vehicle and equipment sales, and claims administration businesses.

We operate a network of licensees in provision of our services worldwide and are affiliated to many other companies through ownership. As our licensees and affiliates are independent companies, they are not owned or controlled by us and are not covered by this policy, although they may have their own privacy policies to govern the personal data they collect. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of our licensees and affiliates.

 _ **More about subsidiaries, licensees and affiliates** …_

 _ **Subsidiaries:** These companies are owned by The Hertz Corporation and are covered by this policy. The expressions “we”, “us” and “our” apply to them, except for Dollar Thrifty Automotive Group, Inc. which operates the Dollar Rent A Car and Thrifty Rent A Car businesses, Firefly Rent A Car, LLC, and Donlen Corporation which operates a fleet leasing and fleet management business._

 _ **Licensees:** We have a network of independent companies licensed to operate vehicle or equipment rental businesses using the “Hertz” name and business system. These companies may describe themselves as “Hertz System Licensees” or “Hertz Franchisees” to indicate that they are not our subsidiaries._

 _ **Affiliates:**  These companies either control us (through ownership) or are controlled by the companies that control us. They cover a range of businesses but are generally not involved in provision of our services to you. _  

 **Legal issues  
** \--------------------------------------------------------

We do business in many countries and aim to comply with the privacy laws applicable to the personal data we collect and use. 

The Hertz Corporation and those of its subsidiaries operating within the United States of America, comply with the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, retention and use of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

 **Changes   
**\--------------------------------------------------------

We may change this policy from time to time. If we do so, the amended policy will take effect when we post it on our website. We will amend the “ **last updated** ” notice on the first page of this policy whenever we make a change. 

If any change makes the policy less protective of your personal data, it will not apply to data we collected about you before the change was made. The only exception to this is where we have told you about the changes and given you the opportunity to tell us not to apply them to your personal data.

 **COLLECTION  **

We collect a range of data about you from a variety of sources for the purposes of our business. The examples we provide here are illustrative rather than a complete list of our practices.

 **What we collect  
** \--------------------------------------------------------

We collect the personal data and the non-personal data we need to provide the services you request from us and for our operational uses in connection with such services, which may include:

  * Name, address and contact details, including telephone and mobile number, and email;

  * Date and place of birth, passport number and driver’s license number and, upon our request, a copy of your driver’s license;

  * Employer(s) name and address;

  * Credit card information;

  * Frequent flyer and other membership reward or loyalty program information;

  * Affiliations with companies, associations, colleges or cities;

  * Location data such as geographic location of electronic devices used to contact us or to access our mobile “apps” or of the vehicle or equipment you have rented;

  * Information regarding the vehicle or equipment rented and its operation during your rental;

  * Rental charges you incur and other information relating to your transactions;

  * Information transmitted by your computer’s browser software;

  * Itinerary information; and
  * Information about your credit history or other publicly available information about you from consumer reporting agencies.

We may collect personal data which is regarded as sensitive data in some countries, such as data about health conditions or membership of a trade union, which we are unable to process without your consent.

 _ **More about  sensitive data…**_

 _Data about your **health conditions** is regarded as sensitive in many countries. If you ask us to accommodate a disability, such as by provision of hand controls, or if there is an accident and we need to work with insurance and claims management companies relating to any injury you may incur, we may need to process data about your health conditions.  Similarly, in the EU, at least, your **membership of a trade union** or similar organization is regarded as sensitive and we may need to process this information if you use a CDP Number that only members of that union or organization can use._

 _Please note that **if you wish to rent with us or our licensees and need to provide sensitive data, you consent to that data being collected, used and disclosed for our Operational Uses.**  We will not use sensitive data about you for marketing purposes._  

 **Sources    
**\--------------------------------------------------------

We collect personal data directly from you in connection with a reservation (even an abandoned or interrupted reservation), a rental of a vehicle or equipment, or your membership in any of our membership programs, including information you provide:  

  * When you call our reservation, customer contact or member care centers;

  * On our websites;

  * Through our kiosks;

  * On our mobile “apps”;

  * On our official third party social network pages;

  * Through your computer’s web browser;

  * At rental locations;

  * Through our in-vehicle or in-equipment technology or through other telematic devices; and

  * When you join Hertz membership programs, such as Hertz Gold Plus Rewards or Hertz on Demand 24/7.

We also gather personal data about you from a variety of **other sources** , including:

  * Reservations you make with us through licensees, travel agents or brokers;

  * Transactions you complete with us and our licensees, including options you take, charges you incur and any incidents or accidents that may occur;

  * CDP Sponsors or sponsors of Hertz on Demand 24/7 Promotion Codes or affiliations (as described below);

  * To the extent you have made such information available, from third party social networks;

  * Consumer reporting agencies; and

  * Other companies that have business relationships with us, such as our licensees, affiliates and business partners, including airlines, hotels and insurance companies.

 **Websites  
** \--------------------------------------------------------

 **Our websites**

Certain technologies are used on our websites and on mobile devices to collect data about your visit or usage, as follows:

  **Cookies**

A “ **cookie** ” is a set of data sent to your computer or mobile device by a web server that enables the server to recognize your computer or mobile device.

Cookies help us improve the quality of your visits to our websites by making the reservation process faster and smoother. The information they provide helps us develop content and features that we think will be of interest to you.

We use cookies to: 

  * Track your use of our websites during a single visit, remember the data you provide and the choices you make as you progress from page to page (“ **session cookies** ”); and

  * Recognize you at your next visit (“ **persistent cookies** ”).

Third party cookies may also be used on our websites for the purpose of:

  * Such third parties providing goods or services to you (for example, but without limitation, an insurance carrier paying or reimbursing you for a vehicle or equipment in connection with insurance replacement rentals);

  * Performing services on our behalf;

  * Facilitating business transactions with or through such third parties; or

  * Providing advertisements to you.

 ** _More about cookies…_**

 _By adjusting your browser or installing certain software, you can restrict our use of cookies.   If you do this, you should be aware of the following:  _

 _•  If you restrict our use of **session cookies** you will not be able to use our websites or certain features of our e-mail messages. You should be aware that session cookies are generally deleted or made unavailable to us as soon as you close your browser._

 _•  If you restrict our use of **persistent cookies** you may still enjoy the full workings of our websites and e-mail messages but will need to re-enter some data when starting a new website session. Although persistent cookies will neither automatically be erased nor made unavailable to us upon closing your browser, they will typically “expire” after a number of years._

 _If you are still unsure about cookies, please note that our cookies are unable to retrieve other data from your computer’s hard drive or pass on computer viruses._    

  **Pixel tags**

In addition, “ **pixel tags** ”, “web beacons”, “JavaScript”, or similar technologies that enable, among other things, the tracking of your actions as a user of various websites or recipient of e-mail messages. (“Pixel Tags”) may be used. Pixel Tags may be used in connection with our web pages, our online advertising, or our e-mail messages, either by Hertz or by our service providers, business partners or other third parties.

Pixel Tags are used to collect typically anonymous data to help identify types of information, including popular destinations, average rental prices, quote and conversion rates, click-throughs and other information to improve the service you receive or the relevance of advertising directed to you. Pixel Tags may also be used to identify which online advertisement or email has brought you to a website.

 Further, certain Pixel Tags may be used by other companies for the purpose of tracking visits to their websites, identifying if such internet traffic came from a Hertz website or confirming your eligibility to receive services or benefits from such other companies.

As the internet and other eCommerce channels continue to develop, we may deploy and utilize different types of technologies to collect data regarding your visit or usage.

  **Blogs or Message Boards** Some of our websites and our official corporate pages on third party social networks (such as Facebook) may provide functionality that permits you to post public messages or responses to articles, comments or other postings. You should be aware that by submitting such a posting, including any personal data or non-personal data in connection with it, you intend for that posting and any data in connection with it to be, and it shall immediately become, public and as such will not be subject to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to remove any posting or content in a posting at our sole discretion.

 **Other company websites**

Our websites and e-mail messages may contain links to websites operated by other companies. You should be aware that the collection and use of any data you provide on these websites will be governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the website and not by this policy.

 **RETENTION**

We try to ensure that the personal data we retain about you is stored securely and, in light of the information provided to us, is as accurate, current and complete as necessary for the purposes for which we use it.

 **Storage  
** \--------------------------------------------------------  
We generally retain personal data about our customers for as long as we believe appropriate for the purposes for which it was collected or as otherwise required by applicable law.

 Our principal databases for storing the personal data we collect are located in Oklahoma, U.S.A., except for the Hertz on Demand 24/7 database, which is principally located in France and the Navigation Solutions, LLC database, which is principally located in Texas, U.S.A.

 **Security  
** \--------------------------------------------------------

As you may be aware, there is no completely secure method of transmitting or storing data. Although their physical characteristics are different, postal mail, telephone calls, text messages, faxes and transmissions over the Internet all present possibilities of loss, misrouting, interception and misuse of the data that is transmitted.

We take reasonable measures to protect against the loss, misuse and unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration and destruction of your personal data by aiming to maintain appropriate physical, procedural and electronic safeguards to protect your personal data, including:

  * Restricting access to personal data to our employees on a “need to know” basis; 

  * Enforcing policies and procedures for our employees in their handling of personal data; and

  * Using technologies designed to safeguard data during its transmission, including SSL encryption for the data you provide on our websites. 

If you have reason to believe that any account with us is no longer secure, you must immediately contact us by following the instructions at the end of this policy. 

 _ **More about  SSL encryption…**_

 _“SSL” stands for Secure Sockets Layer encryption. We use this protection for the data you submit to us on our websites.  SSL encryption seeks to ensure that you are actually sending your data to Hertz and that no-one else can read or tamper with it during transmission._

 _When you are asked to provide your personal data to us on our website, you will see that our “http” website address changes to read "https". The additional “s” denotes that the site is secure for that data transfer. You may also see a closed padlock symbol on your screen, again denoting a secure site._

 **Security of communications**

We try to strike a balance between the security of your data and your convenience. As a result, we may sometimes use a method of communication that is less secure than a less convenient alternative.

 For example, but not limitation, we will send you an e-mail or a text message in unencrypted form (i.e. instantly readable) because many of our customers are unable to access encrypted (i.e. coded) e-mail or messages. This means that our message, if misrouted or intercepted, could be read more easily than encrypted messages. For this reason, please do not include confidential information, such as your Hertz Gold Plus Rewards member number or credit card number, in any e-mail or text you send to us or on any posting you make to a public area of a third party social network page, especially since any such posting immediately becomes public.

For a more secure way to communicate with us over the Internet, please click on the “ **Contact Us** ” link on any page of [www.hertz.com](http://www.hertz.com/), [www.connectbyhertz.com](http://www.connectbyhertz.com/ "www.connectbyhertz.com"), or [www.hertzequip.com](http://www.hertzequip.com/ "www.hertzequip.com") or initiate a Live Chat session via [www.neverlost.com](http://www.neverlost.com/), and follow our instructions.

 **Access  
**

\--------------------------------------------------------

You may access and review your personal data and correct factual errors as follows:

  * If you are a member of a Hertz membership program, such as Hertz Gold Plus Rewards, or similar program, you may update your member profile by logging into the Hertz Gold Plus Rewards section of [www.hertz.com](http://www.hertz.com/).

  * If you are a member of Hertz on Demand 24/7, you may update your member profile in the My Account section of [www.hertzondemand.com](http://www.hertzondemand.com/) or by telephone. Call  (877) 654-4400 in the United States; 00448708454545 in London; 0033800450400 in Paris; 004969380789020 in Berlin; and 0034912757227 in Madrid.

  * If you have a Hertz NeverLost.com profile, you may update your user profile information in the My Account section of www.neverlost.com or by calling NeverLost Customer Service at (800) 823-2547 in the United States.

  * If you are not a member of a Hertz membership program, or your interest is broader than your membership data, or you wish us to delete certain of your personal data, please contact us by following the instructions at the end of this policy.

To protect your privacy and the security of your personal data, we will take steps to verify your identity before granting you access or making corrections to the data we store about you.

Certain types of personal data may need to be updated with the third party social network through which you may interact with us, rather than directly with us.

 **USES**

Your personal data will not be used in a way that is incompatible with the purpose for which it was collected or as authorized by you. In that regard, by enrolling in a Hertz membership program or making a reservation with us, you consent to our use and disclosure of your personal data for the operational uses listed below. We would also like to use your data for marketing purposes. 

 **Operational uses  
** \--------------------------------------------------------

The examples provided below are illustrative and not a complete list of our practices:

 **To provide you services**  

We will share your personal data among ourselves, our agents, and our licensees and other companies to provide services to you, including to:

  * Make your rental reservations; 

  * Process your transactions; 

  * Provide you with enhanced rental services, such as services provided in connection with Hertz membership programs and similar services;

  * Provide you services in connection with your rental; such as navigation assistance or itinerary planning;

  * Provide you with customer assistance, including, but not limited to, assistance after you have initiated but not completed a reservation; 

  * Bill and collect amounts owed in connection with your rentals and membership(s); and

  * For customer satisfaction and market research purposes to help us improve our services.

 **To communicate with you**

We may use your personal data to communicate with you regarding:

  * Any reservation you initiate or rental transaction;

  * Your membership/status in a Hertz membership program; or

  * Changes to the terms or features of any Hertz membership program to which you belong.

So that we may communicate with you, you give us your consent to call you on or send text messages to your mobile telephone/device. You also consent to our use of auto-dialers and pre-recorded messages in connection with any such telephone call or text message, including calls or texts to mobile telephone numbers. We will not charge you for such calls or texts. Your mobile service provider will charge you according to the applicable plan to which you subscribe.

 **Disclosure to companies you use**   

We will also share your information with companies you use in connection with your rental, including:  

  * Your credit card provider and other companies that process your charges; 

  * Any company or organization that is paying your rental charges; 

  * Any intermediary you use, such as a travel agent or broker, in relation to any aspect of your rental; and 

  * Any operator of a membership program for which you are rewarded for renting with us, such as a frequent flyer program.

You may quote a special discount code, called a “ **CDP number** ”, when you rent with Hertz, entitling you to the special rate or benefits we may have negotiated with your company, association, credit card company or travel club (the “CDP Sponsor”). By using a CDP number, you consent to our disclosure of your personal data to the CDP Sponsor.

 _ **More about   CDP Sponsors…** _

 _If you rent using a CDP (Customer Discount Program) number, you consent to our disclosure of your personal data to the CDP sponsor to:  
_

 _• Administer and evaluate the program;_

 _•  Confirm your eligibility to rent using that CDP number;_

 _•  Determine our compliance with the terms of the program;  
• Establish your compliance with the sponsor’s rental policies;  
• Enable the sponsor’s payment of your rental costs (if applicable); or  
• For any other uses reserved by a CDP sponsor with you, which may include marketing uses._

 _If you do not wish us to disclose your personal data to a CDP sponsor for the above purposes, you must not use their CDP number for your rental or as part of your profile.. This will mean, however, that you will not be able to receive the benefits associated with that CDP number._

Hertz on Demand 24/7 members may enroll for membership under a “Promotional Code” or an “affiliation” with a college, company, association or city. Hertz on Demand 24/7 may use these organizations to help administer the services that it offers. By enrolling under a Promotional Code or affiliation with a college, company, association or city, you consent to our disclosure of your personal data to them for their and our administrative purposes or such other purposes as may be agreed upon between you and such Hertz on Demand 24/7 Promotional Code or affiliation sponsor.

 **More about Hertz on Demand 24/7 Promotion Codes or affiliation sponsors …**

 _If you do not wish us to disclose your personal data to a Hertz on Demand 24/7  Promotional Code or affiliation sponsor, do not use the Promotional Code or reference the affiliation sponsor when you enroll in Hertz on Demand 24/7 or follow the instructions above to access your Hertz on Demand 24/7 member profile and remove the Promotional Code or affiliation sponsor reference from it._

 **Protective and legal uses**

We may use, share and disclose your personal data for legal reasons as we believe necessary or appropriate, including:

  * under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence;

  * to process, handle or otherwise respond to claims for damages, including claims or demands for bodily injury or property damage;

  * to comply with legal process;

  * to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence;

  * to enforce our terms and conditions;

  * to recover our vehicles, equipment or any monies due, such as through debt collection agencies;

  * to protect our operations or those of any of our subsidiaries;

  * to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our subsidiaries, you or others; and

  * to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

 **Disclosure to our agents**

We may use other companies as our service providers or agents to act on our behalf and assist us in the conduct of our business, performing services for us under our instruction. These services may include hosting certain websites or databases, operating “apps” for us on our social media networks’ pages, running contests, sweepstakes and other promotions for us, sending marketing communications, carrying out data analysis and conducting customer satisfaction surveys or other research. We will seek to require our service providers and agents to maintain appropriate security standards to protect your personal data and use the personal data we provide to them only for the purposes we specify.  

 **Disclosure for corporate transactions**

We may disclose your personal data to a third party in connection with any contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

 **Marketing uses  
**

\--------------------------------------------------------

We may aggregate your personal data and use it to develop marketing programs and service offerings that we believe may be of interest to you. We would like to send these to you by email, by text message or by mail. We would also like to share your personal data with our licensees, affiliates and business partners for their marketing purposes. You have choices in relation to our marketing uses of your personal data, based upon the residence for you in our records, as follows:

 **US residents**

We may use your personal data for the above marketing purposes, although you can choose to limit or restrict our mailings and our sharing of your data for these uses by following the instructions at _Marketing Options_ below.  

 **EU residents**

We will only use your personal data for our marketing purposes with your prior consent, which may be collected from a number of sources.  

If you do not receive marketing messages from us and would like to do so, or if you want to limit or restrict our mailings or sharing of your data for marketing purposes, please follow the instructions at _Marketing Options_ below.

 **Residents of other countries**

We aim to comply with your local law regarding our use of your personal data for marketing purposes. You can instruct us how we can use your personal data for marketing purposes by following the instructions at Marketing Options below.

 **Marketing Options**

\--------------------------------------------------------

 **Members of Hertz or Connect by Hertz programs**

If you are a member of Hertz Gold Plus Rewards, Hertz on Demand 24/7 or a similar membership program, you will have made marketing choices when you enrolled or at such other time(s) as you may have chosen to do so. These choices are now recorded in your Profile. You can review and amend your selections by accessing your Profile at the Hertz Gold Plus Rewards section on www.hertz.com. You can review and amend your Hertz on Demand 24/7 selections by accessing your Profile on the Log In section on [www.hertzondemand.com](http://www.hertzondemand.com/). You can review and amend your Hertz NeverLost selections by accessing your Profile on the My Account section on www.neverlost.com.

 Alternatively, please complete the My Privacy Choices form at the end of this policy and mail it to us, following the instructions at Contact Us below.

 **Non-members**

We may record your privacy election regarding the receipt of marketing communications at the time you make a reservation or at other times when you interact with us. If you are not then a member of one of our membership programs, or the email address provided for the specific reservation/interaction is not associated with the profile you have in a membership program, you can follow the “Alternate opportunities to opt-out” instructions below to tell us that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications at that email address if you previously had elected to receive marketing communications.

 In addition, if you are not a member of one of our membership programs, you can record your marketing choices by enrolling, free of charge, in Hertz Gold Plus Rewards. Please either ask at the rental counter or visit our Hertz Gold Plus Rewards section on [www.hertz.com](http://www.hertz.com/).

 When you enroll, we will provide you with a Hertz Gold Plus Rewards member number and ask you to quote it when you rent a vehicle from Hertz.  We will automatically apply your marketing choices to all Hertz rentals you make quoting this number. Your choices will be recorded in your Hertz Gold Plus Rewards Profile and you will be able to amend your choices at any time by following the instructions for _Members of Hertz membership_   _programs_ above.

 **Alternative opportunities to opt-out**

Our marketing emails contain an unsubscribe option.  If you do not want us to continue to send marketing emails to your email address, click on ‘ _unsubscribe_ ’ and we will not send further marketing emails to that address, although you may still receive emails at other addresses for which you have not unsubscribed. If you subsequently wish to override your choice to unsubscribe, you will need to either amend your Profile (see _Members of Hertz  or Connect by Hertz programs_) or, if you are not a member of one of our programs, follow the instructions for  _Non-members_ above.

 **Important points to note**

Please note the following points about the marketing choices you make:

  * If you change your marketing choices, we will always observe your most recent choice associated with your Hertz or Connect membership number. Although we aim to process your choices promptly, you may still receive marketing communications prepared before we received your request to unsubscribe; 

  * If you change your address, we will continue to follow your directions for your most recent address provided from your ‘unsubscribe’ click above, your Profile, or the My Privacy Choices form you completed that is associated with your Hertz or Connect by Hertz membership number. In order for us to continue to follow your directions at a new address, you will need to update your Profile online or complete another My Privacy Choices form with your updated information and provide it to us with your changed contact information; and 

  * If you choose not to receive marketing messages from us, you may not be able to receive certain benefits connected to your program, such as Hertz Gold Plus RewardsTM points and free rental days (if applicable). You will, however, continue to receive program updates and other membership information; and

  * If your Profile contains a customer discount program (CDP) number or you enrolled for Hertz on Demand 24/7 with a Promotion Code (PC) or through an affiliation, your CDP, PC or affiliation sponsor may have made marketing choices for users of that CDP, PC or affiliation. If the sponsor’s choices are more restrictive on our use of your data than your choices, we will observe the choices made by the sponsor in connection with those transactions in which such CDP, PC or affiliation is used.

 **Contact Us**

We hope this policy answers your questions about our collection and use of your personal data. If you have additional questions or want to contact us for a specific purpose, please select from the following:

 ** _Access/Corrections:_**  Please send any request to access, amend or delete certain personal data we hold about you to the most convenient address below.

 ** _General questions:_**  You should send any questions you may have about this policy to the most convenient address below. If you feel our response is not satisfactory, we will refer you to a neutral and independent dispute resolution organization.

 ** _Marketing:_**  Send a completed _My  Privacy Choices_ form (at the end of the policy) to the most convenient address below. We aim to process your choices promptly on receipt, but you should please allow a number of days for your choices to become effective.

 ** _Security:_**  If you have reason to believe that the personal data we hold about you, such as your Hertz Gold Plus Rewards member number, other program Profile, or Hertz on Demand 24/7 membership information is no longer secure, you must immediately notify us of the problem by either clicking “Contact Us” on any page onof [www.hertz.com](http://www.hertz.com/), [www.hertzondemand.com](http://www.hertzondemand.com/), [www.hertzequip.com](http://www.hertzequip.com/); initiating a Live Chat session via [www.neverlost.com](http://www.neverlost.com/); or calling as follows:

  * Customers in the United States: (800) 654-4173

  * Customers outside the United States: 001 (405) 775-3400

  * For Hertz on Demand 24/7, you may call (800) 654-4173 in the United States; 00448708454545 in London; 0033800450400 in Paris; 004969380789020 in Berlin; and 0034912757227 in Madrid

  * For Hertz NeverLost customers, you may call (800) 823-2547 in the United States

 ** _US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Enforcement:_** Please raise any concerns regarding our compliance with the US-EU Safe Harbor Principals and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles by clicking “Contact Us” on any page of [www.hertz.com](http://www.hertz.com/), [www.hertzondemand.com](http://www.hertzondemand.com/), or [www.hertzequip.com](http://www.hertzequip.com/); for Hertz NeverLost customers, by initiating a Live Chat session via [www.neverlost.com](http://www.neverlost.com/); or writing to us at any of the addresses below.  We have committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Principals and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by us, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.

 ** _Contact addresses:_** • Director, Privacy Services, The Hertz Corporation, P.O. Box 25301, Oklahoma City, OK 73125, U.S.A.

• Director, Privacy Services, Hertz Europe Service Centre, Swords Business Park, Swords, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland

• Privacy Compliance Officer, Hertz Australia Pty Limited, Level 6, 10 Dorcas Street, South Melbourne VIC 3205, Australia

• Director, Privacy Services, Hertz New Zealand Ltd., Private Bag 4716, Christchurch, New Zealand 8020

• Manager, Customer Service, Navigation Solutions, LLC, 334 N. Central Expressway, Suite 210, Plano, TX 75074, U.S.A.

 **My  Privacy Choices  
**\--------------------------------------------------------

Please complete this form and send it to us by following the instructions at  _Contact Us_ above.

(Updates: Please update your information in your Profile online, or use this form for changes.)

 _ **Please note** : Privacy Choices for our Dollar Rent A Car, Thrifty Rent A Car, or FireFly Rent-A-Car businesses or Donlen Corporation should be made by following instructions in their respective privacy policies._

Name:  
.......................................................................  
---  
Address: ........................................................................| State/Province: ................................................................  
Zip/Post code: ........................................................................| Country: .................................................................  
Email Address: ........................................................................| Hertz Gold Plus Rewards Member Number: .................................................................  
  
Hertz on Demand 24/7 Membership #  
........................................................................  
  
A. Please send me marketing offers and materials from Hertz:

                                                                  **Yes           No**

  Postal mail                                                [  ]          [  ]

  E-mail                                                       [  ]          [  ]  

B. Please share my personal data with Hertz’s licensees, affiliates and business partners for their marketing purposes:

                                                                  **Yes           No**

                                                                  [  ]          [  ]
